Joel Mounts

joelmounts@gmail.com ❖ (616) 780-3265 ❖ joelmounts.com ❖ Github

INTRO: Frontend engineer with 2 years of experience building applications in TypeScript and Vue.js for high-ticket clients, with additional projects in React, Svelte and Astro. Business-minded, proactive, independent problem-solver focused on constantly adding value to teams and projects; passionate about useful products and clean code.

SELECTED WORK EXPERIENCE

Stratacache July. 2022 – Present

Frontend Engineer - Vue 2/3, Javascript/Typescript, HTML/CSS, Git, Jira, Storybook

Dayton, OH

- As Application Developer, I translate designs from Tim Hortons, McDonalds and other clients into Vue apps
 - O Taco Bell redesign: contributed ~20% of code to current menu boards in the field
 - o Tim Hortons Canada: serviced constant bi-weekly content changes for 4000+ locations
 - o Tim Hortons US: responsible for application builds & deployments, including close work with QA
- i18n: Maintained multi-language support, including 4 variations of French & English combinations
- Project Standardization: Standardized code bases, including Documentation, Prettier/linting, node & node
 module versions, proprietary components, branching strategies and branch cleanup for 5 major client projects
- Internal Tooling: Worked on several components for a frontend UI Library, each with multiple stories and
 tests; implemented these components across a range of internal tools to standardize brand, feel and functionality

Debatetrack March 2019 – Present

Webmaster / Content Creator

Online

- Debatetrack is an education brand for high-school debate clubs, publishing free & paid learning materials
- As Webmaster / Content Creator, I research & record lectures for YouTube & manage marketing & sales:
 - Email list management: 0-3000 in a ~10000-customer niche, 50%+ open rates and 10% sales conversion
 - o Top-of-funnel: create & maintain content funnel

ThatAPICompany

March 2022 - July 2022

Application Developer - Javascript, HTML/CSS, React, Git

Online

Developed demo applications for educational APIs, including the famous Cat API – demo here

University of Arkansas Department of Chemical Engineering

April 2012 – August 2012

Research Assistant

Fayetteville, AR

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATES

Grand Valley State University BS Biopsychology	
Amazon Web Services Solutions Architect Associate	October, 2023 Online
Coding Temple Full-stack Software Certificate	May, 2022 Online

TOOLS, SKILLS & INTERESTS

- Tools: Javascript, Typescript, Python, Vue / React / Svelte, Figma, Git, SQL, APIs, Visual Studio, APIs, GPT
- Skills: Communication, Education, Project Vision, Client Relations, Social Media, Chinese Relations
- Interests: Coffee, Lifting, Chess (1600), Hiking, Cooking, Gaming, Competitive Debate